A Guide to the Records of the Clan MacLeod Society USA, 1899-2009
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Publications 1929-2000.
  - Histories: Individual/Family
    - An American Venture: Letters Home from James and William MacLeod, 1770-1776 1988 (Box-folder 76:15)
    - Autobiography of William James McLeod (photocopy) 1929 (Box-folder 76:16)
    - The Descendants and Family of Lauchlin John McLeod (Box-folder 76:17)
    - The Descendants of Alexander McLeod (Box-folder 76:18)
    - The Francis Loud Family of Massachusetts, Michigan, and Ohio 1985 (Box-folder 76:19)
    - The MacLeods of Arnisdale 1984 (Box-folder 77:1)
    - McLeod, Stovall, Hinkle and Allied Families by Daniel McLeod Peterson (Box-folder 77:2)
    - The MacLeods who went to the Philippines by Anthony Macaulay MacLeod 1982 (Box-folder 77:3)
    - Neal McLeod, Emigrant from the Isle of Skye, Scotland 1774-1961: His Genealogy (Box-folder 77:4)
    - Norman McLeod family: Ancestors and Descendants A.D. 625-1983 and Allied Families (Box-folder 77:5)
    - The Richard McClure Family of Pennsylvania and Ohio 1985 (Box-folder 77:6)
    - The Samuel McClure Family of Arkansas, Oklahoma, and Tennessee, 1790-1985 1985 (Box-folder 77:7)
    - William MacLeod: Progenitor of the Clan in the Bahamas (Box-folder 77:8)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Clan MacLeod family cookbook (Box-folder 77:9)
    - Clarion of Skye magazine and the Highland Trader (fragile condition) (Box-folder 77:10)
    - The Coracle: Journal of the Iona Community (contains article on article on Iona appeal trust fund) November 1961 (Box-folder 78:1)
    - "The Highland Echo" March 30, 1953; April 27, 1953 (Box-folder 78:2)
    - Listing of Clan MacLeod Publications (Box-folder 78:3)
    - The Order of Scottish Clans magazine (fragile condition) (Box-folder 78:4)
    - Picardy by Ronald Vale MacLeod (Box-folder 78:5)
    - Poor Boreraig by Keith Mumby in Piping Times, vol. 28, no. 6: pg. 9-14 (Boreraig is the ancient piping school of the MacCrimmons) March 1976 (Box-folder 78:6)
    - Scottish Field: photograph of Denis Ramsay's portrait of Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod (fragile condition) September 1960 (Box-folder 78:7)
    - Scots magazine: No. 1 (contains interview with Chief John MacLeod of MacLeod) July 2000 (Box-folder 78:8)
    - The Scottish people: Worldwide and International (Box-folder 78:9)
    - The Tatler and Bystander: article Who's who in the Highlands (with picture of Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod and Dunvegan Castle) 1961 (Box-folder 78:10)
    - Ellen Payne Odum Genealogical Library-Family Tree Newsletter (has articles pertaining to Clan MacLeod) June 1992 and June/July 1993 (Box Oversize Box 1)
    - The Scottish Merchant (Clan MacLeod gathering article on page three) March 1984 (Box Oversize Box 1)
- Associated Clan MacLeod Societies (A.C.M.S.) 1935-2009.
  This series is divided into nineteen sub-series of administrative documents, records, and items in regard to the international coordinating agency and parent society of Clan MacLeod worldwide. Sub-series A: Clan MacLeod Heritage Trust; Sub-series B: Clan Centre-Iona Project; Sub-series C: Committees; Sub-series D: Constitution; Sub-series E: Correspondence; Sub-series F: Council Meetings; Sub-series G: Cuillins Mountain Range; Sub-series H: Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod Memorial Trust; Sub-series I: Development Plan; Sub-series J: Election procedures; Sub-series K: Financial; Sub-series L: Genetics Study; Sub-series M: Management Committee; Sub-series N: Migration Project; Sub-series O: Parliament; Sub-series P: Publications; Sub-series Q: Restoration projects; Sub-series R: Workshops; Sub-series S: Miscellaneous. This series is arranged in chronological and alphabetical order.
  - Clan MacLeod Heritage Trust
    - The Clan MacLeod Heritage Trust (I) (Box-folder 78:11)
    - The Clan MacLeod Heritage Trust (II) (Box-folder 78:12)
    - The Clan MacLeod Heritage Trust (III) (Box-folder 78:13)
    - The Clan MacLeod Heritage Trust (IV) (Box-folder 78:14)
  - Clan Centre-Iona Project
    - Correspondence regarding the Clan Centre-Iona Project (I) (Box-folder 79:1)
    - Correspondence regarding the Clan Centre-Iona Project (II) (Box-folder 79:2)
    - Correspondence regarding the Clan Centre-Iona Project (III) (Box-folder 79:3)
    - Correspondence regarding the Clan Centre-Iona Project (IV) (Box-folder 79:4)
    - Correspondence regarding the Clan Centre-Iona Project (V) (Box-folder 79:5)
    - Correspondence: Angus MacLeod and Heritage Lottery Fund (Box-folder 79:6)
    - Fund raising and consultation (I) (Box-folder 80:1)
    - Fund raising and consultation (II) (Box-folder 80:2)
    - Clan Centre committee (Box-folder 80:3)
    - Clan Centre information (Box-folder 80:4)
    - Chief John's involvement (Box-folder 80:5)
    - Inland Revenue Service information (Box-folder 80:6)
    - Proposal for Clan Centre (Box-folder 80:7)
    - Articles in regard to the Clan Centre (Box-folder 80:8)
    - Clan Centre illustration (Box-folder 80:9)
    - Clan Centre pamphlet (Box-folder 80:10)
    - Plans for the Clan MacLeod/Iona Centre (Box-folder 80:11)
    - Reports in regard to the centre (I) (Box-folder 80:12)
    - Reports in regard to the centre (II) (Box-folder 80:13)
    - Virtual Clan Centre website (Box-folder 80:14)
    - Floor plans for Clan Centre (Map-case C4)
    - Drawing and floor plans of the MacLeod of MacLeod Hotel (Clan Centre hotel) (Map-case C4)
  - Committees
    - Alastair Crotach Committee (Box-folder 81:1)
    - Rory Mor Committee (Box-folder 81:2)
  - Constitution
    - By-laws (Box-folder 81:3)
    - Constitution (I) (Box-folder 81:4)
    - Constitution (II) (Box-folder 81:5)
    - Constitution (III) (Box-folder 81:6)
    - Constitution (IV) (Box-folder 81:7)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence 1954-56; 1978-1991 (Box-folder 81:8)
    - Correspondence 1992-1993 (Box-folder 81:9)
    - Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box-folder 82:1)
    - Correspondence 1996-April 1998 (Box-folder 82:2)
    - Correspondence April 1998-July 1999 (Box-folder 82:3)
    - Correspondence August 1999-December 2000 (Box-folder 82:4)
    - Correspondence 2001 (Box-folder 82:5)
    - Correspondence 2002 (Box-folder 82:6)
    - Correspondence 2003 (Box-folder 83:1)
    - Correspondence 2004 (Box-folder 83:2)
    - Correspondence January 2005-September 2006 (Box-folder 83:3)
  - Council Meetings
    - ACMS Council Meetings 1988-1992 (Box-folder 83:4)
    - ACMS Council Meetings 1993-1995 (Box-folder 83:5)
    - ACMS Council Meetings 1996-1998 (Box-folder 83:6)
    - ACMS Council Meetings 1998-1999 (Box-folder 83:7)
    - ACMS Council Meetings 1999-2000 (Box-folder 84:1)
    - ACMS Council Meetings 2001-2002 (Box-folder 84:2)
    - ACMS Council Meetings 2002-2004 (Box-folder 84:3)
    - ACMS Council Meetings 2004-2006 (Box-folder 84:4)
    - Potential meeting places in London (Box-folder 84:5)
    - Meetings questionnaire (Box-folder 84:6)
  - Cuillins Mountain Range
    - Sale of the Cuillins Mountain Range: articles (Box-folder 84:6)
    - Sale of the Cuillins Mountain Range: correspondence (Box-folder 84:7)
  - Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod Memorial Trust
    - Correspondence regarding the Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod Memorial Trust 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 85:1)
    - Declaration of trust by John MacLeod of MacLeod 1978 (Box-folder 85:2)
    - Final accounting closed by trustees December 9, 1989 (Box-folder 85:3)
    - Dame Flora MacLeod memorial: information (Box-folder 85:4)
    - Memorial pledges (Box-folder 85:5)
    - Memorial Trust pamphlet (Box-folder 85:6)
    - Memorial Trust account reports (Box-folder 85:7)
  - Development Plan
    - Development plan 2005 (Box-folder 85:8)
    - Strategic and operational plan (Box-folder 85:9)
  - Election procedures
    - Election procedure for Associated Clan MacLeod Societies (Box-folder 85:10)
  - Financial
    - Financial reports (Box-folder 85:11)
  - Genetics Study
    - Booklet: DNA for Family Historians (Box-folder 85:12)
    - DNA Heritage (Box-folder 85:13)
    - Family Tree DNA (Box-folder 85:14)
    - Genetic study project (I) (Box-folder 85:15)
    - Genetic study project (II) (Box-folder 85:16)
    - Genetic study project (III) (Box-folder 86:1)
  - Management Committee
    - Associated Clan MacLeod Societies Mission Statement (Box-folder 86:2)
    - Associated Clan MacLeod Societies structure/chain of command (Box-folder 86:3)
    - Management Committee meetings 1957, 1965, 1968, 1971, 1973-78, 1980-88 (Box-folder 86:4)
    - Management Committee meetings 1989-1996, 1998 (Box-folder 86:5)
    - Management Committee meetings 2001, 2003, 2004 (Box-folder 86:6)
  - Migration Project
    - Correspondence regarding the migration project 1977, 1979-80, 1985-89, 1990-94, 1999 (Box-folder 86:7)
    - Correspondence regarding the migration project 2000-01 (Box-folder 86:8)
    - Correspondence regarding the migration project 2002-05 (Box-folder 87:1)
    - Genealogy requests 1991, 1998-99, 2001, 2004, 2005 (Box-folder 87:2)
    - Grant application form 1987 (Box-folder 87:3)
    - Jim Ayars (writer of genealogies) (Box-folder 87:4)
    - John Davies (writer of genealogies) (Box-folder 87:5)
    - Jim Hunter (writer of genealogies)(I) (Box-folder 87:6)
    - Jim Hunter (writer of genealogies)(II) (Box-folder 87:7)
    - Jim Hunter (writer of genealogies)(III) (Box-folder 87:8)
    - Research-possibly used by Jim Hunter for Scottish Exodus (?) (Box-folder 87:9)
    - Drafts of Away for a While/Scottish Exodus by Jim Hunter (Box-folder 87:10)
    - Scottish Exodus by Jim Hunter (final draft?) (Box-folder 88:1)
    - Migration committee-Dunvegan proposals (undated) (Box-folder 88:2)
    - Migration project reports (Box-folder 88:3)
    - Possible migration project writers (Box-folder 88:4)
    - Sponsor forms (Box-folder 88:5)
    - Subscriptions/financial records, re. migration project (Box-folder 88:6)
  - Parliament
    - First Clan Parliament 1956 (Box-folder 88:7)
    - Second Clan Parliament 1959 (Box-folder 88:8)
    - Third Clan Parliament 1962 (Box-folder 88:9)
    - Fourth Clan Parliament 1965 (Box-folder 88:10)
    - Fifth Clan Parliament 1968 (Box-folder 88:11)
    - Sixth Clan Parliament 1971 (Box-folder 88:12)
    - Seventh Clan Parliament 1974 (Box-folder 88:13)
    - Eighth Clan Parliament 1978 (Box-folder 88:14)
    - Ninth Clan Parliament 1982 (Box-folder 88:15)
    - Tenth Clan Parliament 1986 (Box-folder 88:16)
    - Eleventh Clan Parliament 1990 (Box-folder 88:17)
    - Twelfth Clan Parliament 1994 (Box-folder 89:1)
    - Thirteenth Clan Parliament 1998 (Box-folder 89:2)
    - Fourteenth Clan Parliament (I) 2002 (Box-folder 89:3)
    - Fourteenth Clan Parliament (II) 2002 (Box-folder 89:4)
    - Fifteenth Clan Parliament (I) 2006 (Box-folder 89:5)
    - Fifteenth Clan Parliament (II) 2006 (Box-folder 89:6)
    - Sixteenth Clan Parliament 2010 (Box-folder 89:7)
  - Publications
    - Clan MacLeod greeting cards and order forms 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 89:8)
    - Magazine correspondence 1955-62, 1967, 1982-83, 1985-88 (Box-folder 89:9)
    - Magazine correspondence 1989-2002, 2004 (Box-folder 89:10)
    - Newsletter 1987-93, 1995-98, 2000-05 (Box-folder 90:1)
    - Newsletter correspondence and questionnaires 1998-99, 2003 (Box-folder 90:2)
    - Clan MacLeod publications: reports (Box-folder 90:3)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1935 (Box-folder 90:4)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1936 (Box-folder 90:5)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1937 (Box-folder 90:6)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1938 (Box-folder 90:7)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1939 (Box-folder 90:8)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1940 (Box-folder 90:9)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1941 (Box-folder 90:10)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1942 (Box-folder 90:11)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1943 (Box-folder 90:12)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1944 (Box-folder 90:13)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1945 (Box-folder 90:14)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1946 (Box-folder 90:15)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1947 (Box-folder 90:16)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1948-1949 (Box-folder 90:17)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1950 (Box-folder 90:18)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1951 (Box-folder 90:19)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1952 (Box-folder 90:20)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1953 (Box-folder 90:21)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1954 (Box-folder 90:22)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1955 (Box-folder 90:23)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1956 (Box-folder 90:24)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1956 souvenir issue (Box-folder 90:25)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1957 (Box-folder 90:26)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1958 (Box-folder 90:27)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1959 (Box-folder 90:28)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1960 (Box-folder 90:29)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1961 (Box-folder 90:30)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1962 (Box-folder 90:31)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1963 (Box-folder 90:32)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1964 (Box-folder 90:33)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1965 (Box-folder 91:1)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1966 (Box-folder 91:2)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1967 (Box-folder 91:3)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1968 (Box-folder 91:4)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1969 (Box-folder 91:5)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1970 (Box-folder 91:6)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1971 (Box-folder 91:7)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1972 (Box-folder 91:8)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1973 (Box-folder 91:9)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1974 (Box-folder 91:10)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1975 (Box-folder 91:11)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1976 (Box-folder 91:12)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1977 (Box-folder 91:13)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1978 (Box-folder 91:14)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1979 (Box-folder 91:15)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1980 (Box-folder 91:16)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1981 (Box-folder 91:17)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1982 (Box-folder 91:18)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1983 (Box-folder 91:19)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1984 (Box-folder 91:20)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1985 (Box-folder 91:21)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1986 (Box-folder 91:22)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1987 (Box-folder 91:23)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1988 (Box-folder 91:24)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1989 (Box-folder 92:1)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1990 (Box-folder 92:2)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1991 (Box-folder 92:3)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1992 (Box-folder 92:4)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1993 (Box-folder 92:5)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1994 (Box-folder 92:6)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1995 (Box-folder 92:7)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1996 (Box-folder 92:8)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1997 (Box-folder 92:9)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1998 (Box-folder 92:10)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 1999 (Box-folder 92:11)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2000 (Box-folder 92:12)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2001 (Box-folder 92:13)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2002 (Box-folder 92:14)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2003 (Box-folder 92:15)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2004 (Box-folder 92:16)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2005 (Box-folder 92:17)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2006 (Box-folder 92:18)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2007 (Box-folder 92:19)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2008 (Box-folder 92:20)
    - Clan MacLeod Magazine 2009 (Box-folder 92:21)
  - Restoration Projects
    - Ardvreck Castle/Historic Assynt (Box-folder 93:1)
    - Duirnish amenity woodland project (Box-folder 93:2)
    - Duirnish Parish Church (Box-folder 93:3)
    - Graveyard restoration project? (Box-folder 93:4)
    - Iona Cathedral trust (Box-folder 93:5)
    - St. Mary's Church and graveyard project (Box-folder 93:6)
    - Queen Victoria School Sports Hall appeal (Box-folder 93:7)
    - Rushen Abbey project (Box-folder 93:8)
    - Trumpan Church (Box-folder 93:9)
  - Workshops
    - Seminars 1994, 1998 (Box-folder 93:10)
    - Workshops 1998, 2001-05 (Box-folder 93:11)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Altanduh Collection project (Box-folder 93:12)
    - Background detail and challenges with ACMS projects (Box-folder 93:13)
    - Clan MacLeod CD-ROM project (Box-folder 93:14)
    - Manuscripts of Major Neil MacLeod (Box-folder 93:15)
    - History of the Associated Clan MacLeod Societies (Box-folder 93:16)
    - Portrait project: Chief John 1999-2001 (Box-folder 93:17)
    - Sponsors for projects (?) (Box-folder 93:18)
    - The Suardal Tapes (Box-folder 93:19)
    - Youth involvement (Box-folder 93:20)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 93:21)
- Clan MacLeod National Societies 1954-2006.
  This series covers the international branches of the Clan MacLeod Society. The series is divided into eight sub-series alphabetically. Sub-series A: Australia; Sub-series B: Canada; Sub-series C: England; Sub-series D: France; Sub-series E: Germany; Sub-series F: New Zealand; Sub-series G: Scotland; Sub-series H: South Africa. This series is arranged in chronological and alphabetical order.
  - Australia
    - Correspondence 1954, 1956, 1960, 2000-02 (Box-folder 94:1)
    - Reports 1980, 1990, 2000, 2003-04 (Box-folder 94:2)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of New South Wales, newsletters November 1955- August 1959; November 1962; May 1967-November 1968 (Box-folder 94:3)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of New South Wales, newsletters February 1969- April, 1974; June 1978 (Box-folder 94:4)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of New South Wales, newsletters 1998-2006 (Box-folder 94:5)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of New South Wales, newsletters: Invitation, 10th Anniversary, MacLeod week at Sydney October 21, 1964 (Box-folder 94:6)
    - Souvenir magazine of Australian tour by Dame Flora October 1-November, 1957 (Box-folder 94:7)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Victoria, newsletters November 1962-1974, 2003-05 (Box-folder 94:8)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Western Australia, newsletters 1956, 1998-99 (Box-folder 94:9)
  - Canada
    - Correspondence 1987, 1989-93, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 94:10)
    - National Council of Clan MacLeod Societies of Canada, newsletter 1987-90 (Box-folder 94:11)
    - The Leod Voice-Newsletter of the National Council of Clan MacLeod Societies of Canada 1998-2006 (Box-folder 94:12)
    - Pamphlet: Clan MacLeod Societies of Canada (Box-folder 94:13)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Central Ontario: general information (Box-folder 94:14)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Central Ontario: celidh announcements (Box-folder 94:15)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Central Ontario: 50th anniversary celebration (Box-folder 94:16)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Central Ontario, newsletter 1962, 1970-75, 1978, 2000-06 (Box-folder 94:17)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Manitoba: general information (Box-folder 95:1)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Manitoba, newsletter 2004-05 (Box-folder 95:2)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Ottawa, newsletter 1998, 2002 (Box-folder 95:3)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of Vancouver Island, newsletter 1970-72, 1991 (Box-folder 95:4)
  - England
    - Correspondence 1988, 1999-2000, 2002-03 (Box-folder 95:5)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of England, newsletter 1989, 1998, 2000, 2002 (Box-folder 95:6)
  - France
    - Correspondence 1997, 2000, 2005 (Box-folder 95:7)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of France, bulletins 1996, 2001-02 (Box-folder 95:8)
  - Germany
    - Correspondence and reports 2001-05 (Box-folder 95:9)
  - New Zealand
    - Correspondence and reports 1955-56, 1958-59, 1961-62, 1970, 1989-90, 1999-2002, 2004-05 (Box-folder 95:10)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of New Zealand, Newsletter 1959-60, 1964, 1967-79, 1990, 1994, 2000-02, 2004-05 (Box-folder 95:11)
    - Loyalty newsletter 1971, 1973, 1974 (Box-folder 95:12)
  - Scotland
    - Newsletter/reports 1990, 1998, 2000, 2004 (Box-folder 95:13)
    - Correspondence 2000, 2002, 2004-06 (Box-folder 95:14)
  - South Africa
    - Correspondence 1999-2000 (Box-folder 95:15)
    - Handbook (Box-folder 95:16)
    - Newsletters 1984-85, 1988, 1990-91, 2006 (Box-folder 95:17)
- Other Scottish-Related Groups, Foundations, and Clans 1973-1998.
  This series pertains to various Scottish clans, councils and groups that would often work with Clan MacLeod. There are three sub-series. Sub-series A: Foundations and Councils; Sub-series B: Other Scottish Clans; Sub-series C: Miscellaneous Groups. This series is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Foundations and Councils
    - American-Scottish Foundation: Scottish Ball and Wallace Awards (Box-folder 96:1)
    - Council of Scottish Clans and Associations, Inc.: correspondence and reports (Box-folder 96:2)
    - Council of Scottish Clans and Associations, Inc.: Certificate of membership for Clan MacLeod (Box-folder 96:3)
    - The Claymore (Council of Scottish Clans and Associations, Inc.) (Box-folder 96:4)
  - Other Scottish Clans
    - Listing of Clan Societies and Scottish Societies from The Highlander March 1, 1979 (Box-folder 96:5)
    - Clan Campbell Society (North America) (Box-folder 96:6)
    - Clan Donald, USA (Box-folder 96:7)
    - The Bee Line: Clan Ferguson newsletters 1973-1979 (Box-folder 96:8)
    - Clan Hamilton (Box-folder 96:9)
    - Hay Happenings: newsletter of the American branch of the Clan Hay Society March and June 1974 (Box-folder 96:10)
    - Clan Mackintosh newsletter February 1981 (Box-folder 96:11)
    - Pipings and MacLeans: vol. 12, no.1 March 1974 (Box-folder 96:12)
    - Clan MacNichol (Box-folder 96:13)
    - Clach NaFaire/The Stone of the Watch: Clan Shaw newsletter Fall 1998 (Box-folder 96:14)
  - Miscellaneous Groups
    - Tufts Kinsmen (Box-folder 96:15)
    - Comhairle Nan Sgoiltean Araich: The Scottish Association of Gaelic Nursery Schools and Playgroups (Box-folder 96:16)
    - North Carolina Scottish Heritage Society (Box-folder 96:17)
    - The St. Andrews Society of the City of Columbia (Box-folder 96:18)
    - The St. Andrews Society of Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 96:19)
    - Scottish-American Military Society (Box-folder 96:20)
    - Scottish Heritage USA, Inc. (Box-folder 96:21)
    - Scottish Society of North Louisiana (Box-folder 96:22)
    - The Order of St. John (Box-folder 96:23)
- Events 1951-2007.
  This series is divided into ten subseries in regard to the many events that took place within or relation to Clan MacLeod. Sub-series A: Coming of Age Ceremony for Future Chief John (1956); Sub-series B: Death of Dame Flora (1976); Sub-series C: Death of Chief John (2007); Sub-series D: Games; Sub-series E: Visits; Sub-series F: Visits-Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod; Sub-series G: Queen's Visit to Dunvegan; Sub-series H: Workshops; Sub-series I: Miscellaneous Events: United States; Sub-series J: Miscellaneous events: Scotland and elsewhere. This series is arranged in chronological and alphabetical order.
  - Coming of Age Ceremony for Future Chief John (1956)
    - Press release of coming of age celebration August 1, 1956 (Box-folder 97:1)
    - Banquet program for coming of age celebration (Box-folder 97:2)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 97:3)
    - United States society gifts to John MacLeod the Younger and Patrick Wolridge Gordon on the occasion of their 21st birthday (Box-folder 97:4)
    - Dutch Treat picnic gathering to celebrate Chief John's coming of age, Paxton Massachusetts August 26, 1956 (Box-folder 97:5)
    - Life Magazine article September 24, 1956 (Box Oversize Box 1)
  - Death of Dame Flora (1976)
    - West Duirnish Parish Church funeral service bulletin 1976 (Box-folder 97:6)
    - Memorials to Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod (Box-folder 97:7)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 97:8)
    - The Passage of the Chief by Milton MacLeod (Box-folder 97:9)
  - Death of Chief John (2007)
    - The death and funeral of Chief John MacLeod of MacLeod February 2007 (Box-folder 97:10)
  - Games
    - Alaskan Scottish Highland Games (Box-folder 97:11)
    - Caledonian Club of San Francisco: 130th Annual Scottish Gathering and Games (Box-folder 97:12)
    - Capital District Scottish Games: Schenectady, New York (Box-folder 97:13)
    - Central New York Games (Box-folder 97:14)